ANDREWS ASAMOAH BOATENG

Accra, Greater Accra Region, Ghana



andrewsboateng137@gmail.com





linkedin.com/in/aaboateng

https://github.com/DreKwasi

Summary

Self-motivated data analyst and Python developer with over 3 years of experience in data analytics and Python development. Implemented cost-saving solutions, including a medication alternatives suggestion app and an order review model, resulting in over \$400K in savings. Proficient in Python, SQL, and Excel with experience in microservice development and data analytics. Seeking to support Bending Spoons' product and engineering teams with insights that can 10x its profitability.

Experience

Customer Solutions Analyst

mPharma - Apr 2021 to Present (1 year 10 months)

- Implemented a supply chain tool using Streamlit to automate alternative medication suggestions, resulting in over \$400K in cost-savings from reduced expiry risks in the first 12 months.
- Created an Order Review Model using Streamlit, Python, and Metabase to streamline monthly orders for proprietary facilities, resulting in \$30K in cost-savings in just one month.
- Improved response times of key revenue drivers by 50% through the creation of dashboards using Google Sheets, Looker, AppScript, and Excel to track revenue growth KPIs.
- Boosted efficiency in data acquisition by developing a mock-up ETL process to automate a set of data quality checks resulting in a 65% decrease in data processing time.

Research Associate (Data Scientist)

West African Centre for Cell Biology of Infectious Pathogens (WACCBIP) - University of Ghana - Jun 2020 to Nov 2021 (1 year 6 months)

- Successfully implemented a Principal Component Analysis to improve the cross-discrimination between biomarkers, resulting in a 50% improvement in feature selection efficiency
- Developed a feature selection algorithm based on Cluster Resolution Feature Selection using python, which identified approximately 10 putative biomarkers from a pool of more than 60 features/biomarkers

Volunteer Research Associate

University of Ghana - Dec 2019 to Present (3 years 2 months)

- Built an ML Classification Model to identify between origins of honey and differentiate pure/adulterated honey products on the Ghanaian market.
- Assisted in training more than 4 project students on employing data science in chemometrics.

Education

University of Ghana (Bachelor of Pharmacy)

Skills

Programming Languages: Python, AppScript, JavaScript, HTML Frameworks: Django, Django REST Framework, jQuery, AJAX Libraries: NumPy, Pandas, Sklearn, TensorFlow, Keras, Vaex

Data Visualization: Jupyter Notebook, Google Sheets, Looker, Streamlit, Metabase

Databases: PostgreSQL, MySQL

Cloud & Version Control: Docker, Heroku, Deta, Git/Github

Methodologies: Functional Programming, Object-Oriented Programming

Projects

QuickHire | Project Link | Dec, 2022 - Present

Collaborated with <u>Joel Anaman</u> to develop a streamlit web app using the Google's Custom Search API to scour job boards via custom search keys

CSGH | Project Link | Nov, 2022 - Present

An All-in-one order processing and inventory web application built with Streamlit

Order Review Model | Project Link | Oct, 2022 – Present

Web Application in Streamlit for Order Validation, Insight Analysis and Flow casting.

Data Science Publication

Evaluation of chemometric classification and regression models for the detection of syrup adulteration in honey - Jun, 2022

Licenses & Certifications

Pharmacist - Pharmaceutical Society of Ghana (License Number: PSGH 5535)